Two Girls Working. Two Girls Working Collection, 2002-2011: A Container List
Two Girl Working Collection, 2002-2011
- Contents: Postcard, two copies and poster. Description: Front Image: Christiane Leach, artist and exhibition curator in an amazing red and purple dress. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Christiane Leach Title: The Definition of Feminine Power Informal Meta Title: None Place: Future Tenant: A Space for Art, 819 Penn Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15222 Start Date: 9/28/2007 End Date: 10/19/2007 Funding Notes: Exhibition funded by the August Wilson Center for African American Culture. Other Notes:, 1.37.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Front image: portraits of Claire, Stephanie, and Vivian. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): Barbara O'Brien Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Trustman Art Gallery, 300 The Fenway, Simmons College, Boston, MA 02115 Start Date: 10/9/2007 End Date: 11/9/2007 Funding Notes: Part of Simmons College's Spinning Straw Into Gold, The Ethics of Production Fall 2007 Exhibition Series. Funded in part by the LEF Foundation and Catherine Hannah Behrend. Other Notes: Designed by Simmons College. Two Girls Working were artists in residence at Simmon College for a week. This postcard detailed our exhibition and panel presentation. We also conducted interview sessions during the residency., 1.38.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Postcard promoting book publication. Includes portraits of Linda, Susan, Towana, Erika, and Stephanie. Event / Exhibition Type: Publication of book by Rutgers University Press. Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: N/A, N/A, N/A Start Date: Book available 10/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: Designed by Two Girls Working before the final cover of the book was selected., 1.39.
- Contents: Galley Description: Pre-publication gallery of book. Partial ARC, uncorrected, not for resale. Event / Exhibition Type: Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Rutgers University Press, 100 Joyce Kilmer Avenue, Piscataway, NJ 08854 Start Date: Book available 10/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: Includes quote by Lucy R. Lippard on the front cover., 1.40.
- Contents: Catalog Description: Rutgers University Press' fall winter 2007 2008 catalogue promoting new publications Event / Exhibition Type: Publication of book by Rutgers University Press. Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Rutgers University Press, 100 Joyce Kilmer Avenue, Piscataway, NJ 08854 Start Date: Book available 10/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: Trappings featured on pages 2-3., 1.41.
- Contents: Book, signed Description: ISBN:978-0-8135-4184-6 Event / Exhibition Type: Publication by Rutgers University Press. Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Rutgers University Press, 100 Joyce Kilmer Avenue, Piscataway, NJ 08854 Start Date: 10/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.42.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Postcard promoting book publication. Includes image of the book cover. Event / Exhibition Type: Publication of book by Rutgers University Press. Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: Place: N/A, Pittsburgh, PA Start Date: 11/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: We designed this as our official book postcard once the cover was finalized., 2.1.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Postcard promoting book publication and signings. Includes image of the book cover. Event / Exhibition Type: New Jersey and New York book signings: 11/6/07, 11/7/07, 11/8/07, 11/10/07,11/11/07 Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: Trappings Book Tour Place: N/A, Pittsburgh, PA Start Date: 11/13/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.2.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Postcard promoting book publication and signings. Includes image of the book cover. Event / Exhibition Type: Pittsburgh book signings: 11/13/07, 11/15/07, 11/17/07. Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: Trappings Book Tour Place: N/A, Pittsburgh, PA Start Date: 11/13/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.3.
- Contents: Print out of back of postcard, print of poster Description: Postcard promoting exhibition and poster included in exhibition window. The poster includes a photo of the collective Art364B. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Jennifer S. Musawwir and Jovana Stokic Title: Art346B: The Collective Informal Meta Title: Place: NYU Windows on the corner of LaGuardia Place and West Third Street, New York, NY 10012 Start Date: 11/7/2007 End Date: 1/16/2008 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Tiffany Ludwig is part of the collective ART364B. She presented a Two Girls Working photographs and audio works titled "Crystal", "Elizabeth", "Louise", and "Anita" as part of her installation in this group show., 2.4.
- Contents: Quad-fold installation brochure, four copies Description: Front image: photographs of installation at Midwife Center with installation title "Trappings: Midwife Center". Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation. Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working. Title: Trappings: Midwife Center Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Midwife Center Place: Midwife Center for Birth and Women's Health, 2825 Penn Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15222 Start Date: 11/16/2007 End Date: 11/2011 Funding Notes: The Heinz Endowments and PA Partners in the Arts Other Notes: The ceiling tiles are still installed at the Midwife Center as of June 2012. The entire project received national recognition from Americans for the Arts' Public Art Network 2008 Year in Review, which noted innovative and exciting public art projects., 2.5.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies. Description: Front image: artists' rendering of photographic ceiling tile with Marguerite Watson's photo. The postcard promotes the opening reception for the installation. Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation. Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working. Title: Trappings: Midwife Center Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Midwife Center Place: Midwife Center for Birth and Women's Health, 2825 Penn Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15222 Start Date: 11/16/2007 End Date: 11/2011 Funding Notes: The Heinz Endowments and PA Partners in the Arts Other Notes: The ceiling tiles are still installed at the Midwife Center as of June 2012. The entire project received national recognition from Americans for the Arts' Public Art Network 2008 Year in Review, which noted innovative and exciting public art projects., 2.6.
- Contents: Postcard, one copy Description: Front image: photograph of All City Waitress Marching Band Event / Exhibition Type: Panel discussion Curator(s): Carey Lovelace Title: Making it Together: Women's Collaborative Art + Community Informal Meta Title: None Place: The Bronx Museum of the Arts, 1040 Grand Concourse, Bronx, NY 10456 Start Date: 3/2/2008 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: Other participants included Wendy Babcox (6+), Uzuma S. Rizvi (Rasa Theater, Visible Collective), Emily Roysdon (LTTR), Faith Wilding (SubRosa), and Carey Lovelace. Moderated by Amy Mackie, New Museum of Contemporary Art. Carey Lovelace is a Trappings participant., 2.7.
- Contents: Bi-fold, 8x10 Description: Cover is white with exhibition title and artist credit. Has a sticker on the back with this exhibition's dates and details. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): Jill Foote-Hutton Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: East Central Gallery, East Central College, 1964 Prairie Dell Road, Union, MO 63084 Start Date: 3/12/2008 End Date: 4/4/2008 Funding Notes: East Central College Foundation Other Notes: This bi-fold promotes the traveling exhibition at East Central College. The gallery was run by Jill Foote-Hutton, Trappings participant., 2.8.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Front image: photograph of "Trappings: Participants" installed, with viewers. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): Gail Goldman and Jose Ruiz Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Bronx River Art Center, 1087 East Tremont Avenue, Bronx, NY 10460 Start Date: 3/7/2008 End Date: 4/12/2008 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.9.
- Contents: Interactive public art clothing label, two copies Description: A card that hangs on clothing hooks. Participants fill out label and return to museum. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition and Commissioned interactive public art clothing label project. Curator(s): Lisa Haatchadoorian. Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Nicolaysen Art Museum, 400 East Collins Street, Casper, WY 82601 Start Date: 5/16/08 End Date: 7/27/08 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Clothing label folded in half to fit in this folder., 2.10.
- Contents: Bi-Fold postcard, three copies. Description: Front image: image of "Trappings: Participants" installed. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition and Commissioned interactive public art clothing label project. Curator(s): Lisa Haatchadoorian Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Nicolaysen Art Museum, 400 East Collins Street, Casper, WY 82601 Start Date: 5/16/08 End Date: 7/27/08 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.11.
- Contents: Postcard, three copies. Description: Front image: portraits of La'Tasha D. Mayes, Tweety Paisano-Suazo, Clara Lee Arnold, Cynthia Cook. Back image: Erika Soveranes Event / Exhibition Type: Multi-part project: national traveling exhibition, and public art project on D-ride buses, billboards, and banners on Central Avenue (Route 66) Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Place: 516 ARTS, D-ride buses, banners on Central Avenue. 516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102 Start Date: 6/13/2008 End Date: 8/16/2008 Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council. Other Notes: Two Girls Working were in residence in New Mexico in February 2008, and opened this exhibition in June. During the residency we produced several interview sessions., 2.12.
- Contents: Tri-fold brochure, two copies. Description: Front image: image of "Trappings: Participants" installed. Event / Exhibition Type: Multi-part project: national traveling exhibition, and public art project on D-ride buses and on banners on Central Avenue. Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Place: 516 ARTS, D-ride buses, banners on Central Avenue. 516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102 Start Date: 6/13/2008 End Date: 8/16/2008 Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council. Other Notes: These were made specifically to be placed in the D-ride buses to advertise the exhibition and public art installations., 2.13.
- Contents: Program guide, two copies. Description: 516 Arts Downtown Albuquerque Program Guide, summer 2008 Event / Exhibition Type: Multi-part project: national traveling exhibition, and public art project on D-ride buses and on banners on Central Avenue. Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Place: 516 ARTS, D-ride buses, banners on Central Avenue. 516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102 Start Date: 6/13/2008 End Date: 8/16/2008 Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council. Other Notes: Two Girls Working appears on pages 13-15., 2.14.
- Contents: Exhibition brochure, four copies. Description: Front image: portraits of Latasha, Tweety, Rocio, Stephanie, Cynthia, Susan, Clara Lee, and Erika Event / Exhibition Type: A new version of the national, traveling exhibition brochure. Included the republication of the essay "the Power of Two" by Patricia C. Phillips, and a new essay "Trappings: Finding Our Stories, Finding Ourselves" by Dr. Kathy Freise, a Trappings partici Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque Place: 516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102 Start Date: 6/13/2008 End Date: 8/16/2008 Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council. Other Notes:, 2.15.
- Contents: Copies of exhibition catalogue. Description: Front image: graphic design of the words "Fe", "in the making", and all of the exhibiting artists names. Event / Exhibition Type: Group exhibition organized by Jill Larsen at Fe Gallery to celebrate Pittsburgh's 250th anniversary and the breadth of visual art being created in Pittsburgh. We exhibited the video "A Discourse On Power (in Eight Parts) and an installation view of the Mi Curator(s): Jurors included: Vicky A. Clark, Joey Kennedy, Janet L. McCall, Katherine Talcott, and Michael Olijnyk. Title: Fe:in the making Informal Meta Title: Place: Fe Gallery, 4102 Butler Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15201 Start Date: 9/12/2008 End Date: 1/10/2009 Funding Notes: Pittsburgh 250 Community Connections and The Sprout Fund funded the exhibition. Other Notes:, 2.16.
- Contents: Photocopy of 3 pages from exhibition catalog. Description: Title page, overview, artist project page Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation. Curator(s): Biljana Ciric Title: Trappings: Shanghai Informal Meta Title: Intrude: Art and Life 366 at Zendai Museum of Modern Art in Shanghai, China Place: Gynecological exam room at the Meinian Health Center, Shanghai, China, Start Date: 10/4/2008 End Date: 12/2008 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Commissioned by the Zendai Museum of Modern Art for their Intrude: Art and Life 366 project., 2.17.
- Contents: Poster Description: Promotes book-signing, with image of book cover. Event / Exhibition Type: Lecture and book signing. Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Carol Woods Assembly Hall, 750 Weaver Dairy Road, Chapel Hill, NC 27514 Start Date: 4/3/2009 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: Organized by Jean Parrish, a Trappings participant., 2.18.
- Contents: Print of gallery label. Description: A copy of the educational label that was displayed with the artwork. Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation. Curator(s): None Title: Trappings Informal Meta Title: Place: Glen Ridge NJ Transit Train Station, Glen Ridge, NJ 07028 Start Date: 5/6/2009 End Date: 9/4/2009 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Exhibition organized by an artist group called GRAPA, Glen Ridge Art Patrons Association., 2.19.
- Contents: No ephemera for this exhibition. Description: Event / Exhibition Type: National, traveling exhibition. Curator(s): Hu Monvan and Ashley Atkins Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Johnson Johnson, One Johnson Johnson Plaza, New Brunswick, NJ 08933 Start Date: 9/3/2009 End Date: 12/5/2009 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.20.
- Contents: Exhibition catalog, three copies. Description: Accordion book Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation. Curator(s): Yolanda Sanchez Title: Trappings: Miami Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Miami Place: Miami International Airport, MIA Gallery, Central Terminal Gallery, Concourse E, Miami, FL 33126 Start Date: 10/2010 End Date: 2/2011 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.21.
- Contents: Print from Two Girls Working website Description: Description of the exhibition published on our website. Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation. Curator(s): Greta Blalock Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Portland Place: Portland International Airport, Portland, OR 97208 Start Date: 4/2011 End Date: 10/2011 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 2.22.
- Contents: Print of article from website. Description: A print of the article "Telling stories in the public realm: what has been removed" which appeared on the website nanomajority. Event / Exhibition Type: Essay. Curator(s): None. Title: "Telling stories in the public realm: what has been taken away" Informal Meta Title: Place: www.nanomajority.com/projects/tiffany-ludwig,, Start Date: 4/2011 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: In April 2011, Art364B, the collective that includes Tiffany Ludwig, had an online exhibition at nanomajority., 2.23.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Authors
Ludwig, Tiffany
Piechocki, Renee
Subjects
Art--Exhibitions
Artists, American
Feminism in art--United States
Group work in art--United States
Interviews
Oral histories
Power (Social sciences)--United States
Women--Interviews--United States
Women--Social conditions--United States
Women artists--United States
Women's clothing--United States